{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "prize": 500,
      "question": "What city is the capital of Ukraine?",
      "options": ["Lviv", "Kyiv", "Odesa", "Kharkiv"],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "prize": 1000,
      "question": "Who is the author of the lyrics of the Ukrainian national anthem?",
      "options": [
        "Mykhailo Verbytskyi",
        "Pavlo Chubynskyi",
        "Ivan Franko",
        "Taras Shevchenko"
      ],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "prize": 2000,
      "question": "What is the longest river in Ukraine?",
      "options": ["Prut", "Dnister", "Dnipro", "Southern Buh"],
      "correctAnswers": [2]
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "prize": 5000,
      "question": "Which city is often called the cultural capital of Ukraine?",
      "options": ["Odesa", "Lviv", "Sumy", "Chernivtsi"],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "prize": 10000,
      "question": "What are the colors of the Ukrainian national flag?",
      "options": [
        "Blue and yellow",
        "Red and black",
        "Green and white",
        "Blue and white"
      ],
      "correctAnswers": [0]
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "prize": 20000,
      "question": "In which year did Ukraine declare independence?",
      "options": ["1990", "1991", "1992", "1993"],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "prize": 50000,
      "question": "What is the highest mountain in Ukraine?",
      "options": ["Petros", "Hoverla", "Pip Ivan", "Brebenskul"],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "prize": 100000,
      "question": "Who wrote 'Zapovit' (Testament)?",
      "options": [
        "Lina Kostenko",
        "Taras Shevchenko",
        "Ivan Franko",
        "Lesya Ukrainka"
      ],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "prize": 200000,
      "question": "Which of these are regional centers (oblast capitals) in Ukraine?",
      "options": ["Sumy", "Cherkasy", "Kramatorsk", "Vinnytsia"],
      "correctAnswers": [0, 1, 3]
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "prize": 400000,
      "question": "Which Ukrainian band won Eurovision 2022?",
      "options": ["Okean Elzy", "Kalush Orchestra", "Jamala", "Ruslana"],
      "correctAnswers": [1]
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "prize": 800000,
      "question": "Which works were written by Lesya Ukrainka?",
      "options": [
        "Forest Song",
        "The Stonecutters",
        "Contra spem spero!",
        "Intermezzo"
      ],
      "correctAnswers": [0, 2]
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "prize": 1000000,
      "question": "In which year was Kyiv first mentioned in chronicles?",
      "options": ["482", "988", "1240", "1362"],
      "correctAnswers": [0]
    }
  ]
}
